A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Special Events and Activities, Exhibits and Exhibitions FA884
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Special Events and Activities, Exhibits and Exhibitions
1958-1986
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA884
1.32 Cubic Feet 3 boxes
3 boxes.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 600-13
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Contains exhibition materials including still images.
DNA; Vivisection; Medical sciences; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Medicine, Preventive; Genetics; China; Medical research; Medical care; Biology -- Research
- Exhibits
  - Arts and Crafts Exhibition. Library, Welch Hall, 1960 October 27-November 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Application form notice. 16 glossy prints, 1-5x7 inch, 15-8x8-inch, #60-1244, 1 proof print sheet.
  - Arts and Crafts Exhibition. Faculty and Students Club, 1964 November 9-15 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Brochure, proof print sheets of orders 64-3323 and 64-3361 by Donald C. Young, 1-5x7 print from 64-3323, 1 8x10 print, two notices by Anne Morris.
  - Arts and Crafts Exhibition. Faculty and Students Club, 1966 May 24-25 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    1 test print 66-1981-J. Shaltis; 1 test print, no number, slightly enlarged to additional frames; 1 test print, no number, demonstration by J. Forest Vey, 18 frames; 14 glossy prints 8xl0-in papers from 66-1981; 1 gloss print 8x10 inc. J. Forest Vey.
  - Arts and Crafts Exhibition. Faculty and Students Club, 1967 November 6-12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Catalogue; Negatives 67-4060 2 x 2 11/15/67, 12 frames.
  - Arts and Crafts Exhibition. Faculty and Students Club, 1971 April 19-May 10 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Catalogue, cross-reference sheet.
  - Arts and Crafts Exhibition. Faculty and Students Club, 1974 April 15-May 3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Catalogue.
  - Arts and Crafts Exhibition. Student and Faculty Club (sic), 1980 May 19-30 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Catalogue; 6 4 x 5 prints.
  - West African Sculpture Exhibition [No. 1]. Caspary Auditorium, 1964 September-October (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Catalogue; 2 professional contact proofs 35 mm; 1 RI contact proof 35 mm; large prints; photocopy of article by Robert Goldwater, RI Review, September-October 1964.
  - Fifty American Prints. Caspary Auditorium, 1965 March 8-April 7 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Triple folder catalogue only.
  - Early Asian Sculpture. Caspary Auditorium, Summer 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Collection of Lester Wolfe. Trial prints and large prints without negatives; catalogue; negative of head; photocopy from RI News May-June 1965.
  - Contemporary Mexican Art. Graduate Students Residence Hall, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Private collection of Lester Wolfe. 70 pictures. circa 61 pictures in folder, prints and negatives. 2 catalogues.
  - Art of the Northwest Coast Indians [No. l] Caspary Auditorium Gallery, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Catalogue [Haida, Kitsan, Nootka, Makah etc.]. Article by Frederick J. Dockstader, "Northwest Coast Indian Art," RU Review, September-October 1965, 8 text-pages, 14 illustrations. 23 pictures of interior views enlarged from 35 mm film to 60x40mm. No negatives.
  - Paintings and Monotypes by Tibor Csernus (1927- ). Caspary Auditorium Gallery, 1966 June-September (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Flyer, undated. Photocopy of letter from Alexander Tomasz, June 1, 1966. Photocopy of letter from Laszlo Papp, October 14, 1966.
  - Ancient Egypt. Caspary Gallery, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Catalogue only.
  - Art of New Guinea. Caspary Gallery, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Two copies of the catalogue. Photocopy of RU Review, Jan-Feb 1967, with cover and 8 pp. of text including 12 illustrations from "Art of New Guinea" by Douglas Newton. One original photo of Mrs. Patricia Berlin [Mitchell] and Prof. S. A. Goudsmit, with copy negative. (5) 67- 2070 4x5 negs, 1 June 1967, with Prof. Theodore Shedlovsky in 3 pictures.
  - Three Centuries of Botany in North America. Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Hall, 1967 March 22-June 14 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Booklet on rag paper, by Bruce R. Voeller and Paul F. Cranefield, 38 pp. Photocopy of RU Review, March-April 1967, cover and 10 text-pages with 7 illustrations, "British Gardens and North American Flora" by Sir George Taylor. Color print of exhibit reception, identifications include M. W. Chase, Cynthia Pierce-Chase, Keffer Hartline, Paul Cranefield, Mabel Bright. (12) 67-1115 35mm negatives.
  - Tibetan Art. Caspary Gallery, Fall 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Catalogue, cover by Reynard Biemiller. 12-5x7-in. glossy prints of 6-armed statuette, different angles. One statuette standing on a donkey-like form. Two 8xl0-in glossy prints of 6-armed statuette standing on, or feet completed by, pig-like animals with human-type arms. Statue from the American Museum of Natural History. [Mrs. Patricia Berlin wrote that this statue was exhibited outside the reading room of Welch Library; that a small wooden part at the feet was separable, and that it was stolen. MWCI. (17) 68-393 4x5 negs. (12) 67-4444 2x2 negs.
  - Special 3-dimensional exhibits. Library, Welch Hall, [Late 1967]; 8 Kodachrome enlargements 6 5/8 × 4 5/8 in. (2 are photographed from different camera positions) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Michael Faraday. In connection with symposia at The Rockefeller University under auspices of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, 100 years after Faraday's death, 1967 December 26-1968 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    1) 26 Dec 1967: Faraday as a Natural Philosopher. 2) 29 Dec 1967: Faraday and the Unity of Natural Forces. Catalogue. Cover and 9 text-pages. No photos.
  - Stringed Instruments, from the collection of Mr. and Mrs. Laurence C. Witten II. 20-24 May 1968, in connection with the Conference on Scientific Aspects of Musical Instruments. Catalogue, 16 pp., written by Mr. and Mrs. Witten II, 1968 May 20-24 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Photocopy from RU Review, March-April 1968, "Feedback Phenomena between the Stringed Instrument and the Musician," by Georg von Békésy, 9 text-pages, 10 illustrations. 68-2620 (31) -35 mm, (24) 2x2 in.
  - Indonesian Art. Caspary Gallery, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Catalogue, 55 items from collection of Prof. Lee Gildart. (7) 8x10 prints. (16) 68-2720 4x4 negs, 6 June 1968.
  - Temperas and Drawings and Lajos Szalay (1909- ). Caspary Gallery, 1968 September-December 31 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Catalogue with 50 items, as photocopy. Triple-fold, with 7 illustrations.
  - Images [Jekabs Zvilna]. Faculty and Students Club, 1969 April 21-May 2 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Broadside only.
  - Woodcarvings of the Northwest Coast Indians [No. 2]. Caspary Auditorium Gallery, Spring 1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Catalogue. No photographs.
  - Kinetic Art. Caspary Gallery. Catalogue, 1970 May-June; 12 items. No photographs. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - West African Sculpture [No. 2] [Photographed in 1971]. Caspary Auditorium, Fall 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Prints only (one-of-a-kind) [8 rolls 71-2226 A-H]. Two catalogues.
  - West African Sculpture continued, 35 mm negatives (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sculpture, Minoru Niizuma (1930-). Caspary Gallery, Spring 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Photocopy of catalogue listing 11 works. Glossy prints from 35 mm film, enlarged to 4¾"x3 3/8" (5 views in all) [One of exhibits was purchased by David Rockefeller; No. 5 was purchased by The Rockefeller University, "Mouth of River" and placed on cement block before Caspary Hall. MWCJ. Kodacolor prints contributed as final prints (2) or reproductions from Kodacolor negatives owned by Mrs. Patricia Berlin. Picture of sculpture in final location before Caspary Hall.
  - Eskimo Artifacts. Caspary Gallery, Winter 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Two copies of catalogue. Nine 5x7-in. glossy prints, including one of empty case where contents were stolen from Caspary Gallery. [N. B. Photography made after the theft]. Three strips of 35 mm. negatives called 72-E. A.
  - Nicolaus Copernicus (1473-1543). 500 years after his birth (Quin-centennial), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Catalogue, 43 photographs taken for the Lake District Social-Cultural Association in Warmia, Poland, 4 pp. Catalogue for simultaneous exhibition at the IBM Exhibit Center, Madison Ave. & 57th St., N. Y. C. 8-fold catalogue, 16 pp. Exhibits pictured, not numbered.
  - Scientific Instruments (75th anniversary exhibit). Caspary Gallery, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Photographs of recording ellipsometer of Alexander Rothen, before shipping to him in Switzerland (Item 32 of catalogue), with negatives. 3rd printing of catalogue, April 1977. (2) 35 mm negatives and proof sheets from M. W. Chase.
  - Graphic Services, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    2 8x10 prints contributed by Robert J. Keiber and taken by him, partial identification.
  - Other art on exhibit: Pop art in South Laboratory, 1965 April (Box 2, Folder 8)
    65-1225, (8) 35 mm. pictures. Modern sculpture by James Rosati, 68-4808, 1968, out-of-doors on RU campus, (20) 35 mm photographs, (4) 4x5. 2 negatives of the Kline painting in AARH, 7 negatives of other paintings in AARH collection, 1 print each of preceding.
  - Index cards (originals and photocopy) of exhibitions compiled by Merrill W. Chase, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Duplicates of printed brochures (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - CAFETERIA EXHIBITION (originally created for 75th anniversary celebration, 1976)
    - Exhibition, 35 mm. negatives, captions and diagrams (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Convocation, 1959; Print and copy negative (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Media room, Original print and copy negative (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Conn, Alfred E. portrait, 1937; 8×10 copy negative and contact print (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Horsfall, Frank portrait, 1959; (#10054-7) 8×10 copy negative and contact print (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Loeb, Jacques portrait, 1923; (#4491-7) 8×10 copy negative and contact print (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Pearce, Louise, undated; 8×10 copy negative, contact print, and enlargements (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Stanley, Wendell M., undated; 8×10 copy negative and contact print (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Woolley, D. Wayne portrait, 1963; Neg. #63-1401, 8×10 copy negative and contact print (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Board of Scientific Directors, 4×5 copy negative (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS EXHIBITION (originally created for 75th anniversary celebration)
    - Model 990 Peptide Synthesizer. Bruce Merrifield's Model. Model 121M Amino Acid Analyzer, Neg. #9891, Color negative and enlargement (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Addendum to Exhibit, 1 color print (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Ultramicrotomes on display, 2 B & W prints (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Micromanipulators on display, 1 B & W print (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Photocopy of addendum to catalog. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Scientific Instruments Exhibit. From Merrill W. Chase, 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Related Materials
    Received January 14, 1985.
    Photocopy and negative of patient with pacemaker. [See catalogue, Original number 37A. Developed by Drs. Lawrence Eisenberg and Alexander Mauro, in collaboration with Dr. W. W. L. Glenn, 1961-64].
  - The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research. Smoker and Scientific Exhibits in connection with the 55th General Meeting of the S.A.B. [Society of American Bacteriologists], 1955 May 9; pamphlet (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Addition: Janary 7, 1986.
  - Rockefeller Institute Art Exhibition, 1958 October; pamphlet (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Addition: January 7, 1986.
  - RU Art Exhibition. Founder's Hall Lobby, 1986 February 27-March 14; pamphlet (Box 3, Folder 15)